The true King within the walls...
...Rod Reiss and his devious
schemes were foiled.
The Scouts succeeded in
rescuing Eren and Historia.
However...
Appearing before them was...
...Rod Reiss, transformed into a Titan.
Because I wanted to believe my father.
I didn't want my father to hate me...
But now, it's time to say goodbye.
When you're Queen, you can
punch that runt in the face.
How do you intend to evacuate
the citizens in time?
We won't evacuate.
We'll have the citizens remain
in Orvud District just as they are.
"Ruler of the Walls"
What the hell are you thinking, Erwin?!
Keep the citizens in the
city without evacuating?!
By the time it's dawn,
that Titan will be all over us!
That Titan is an Abnormal.
What the hell does that even mean?!
The target Titan is strangely attracted
to high concentrations of people.
Hence, Abnormal.
It means the fellow will turn
a blind eye to a small village,
ignoring it in favor of
reaching this fortified city.
If right now, you were to evacuate
the citizens within Wall Sina,
it would be drawn towards them,
destroying the wall and all in its path.
In the end, it would reach Mitras,
with the greatest density of people...
...and deliver a devastating
blow to humanity.
On our way back, we attempted to use Eren
Jaeger's power to control Titans, but...
...Rod Reiss' Titan showed no reaction.
Stop, Titan!
Hey, stop! I'm talking to you!
Can't you hear me, idiot?!
Rod Reiss, that means you!
You tiny old man!
If we are to stop that Titan, we must do so
outside the walls of Orvud District.
For that to happen, we must
have the citizens act as bait.
However, this does not change the fact
that our first duty as soldiers
is to protect the citizens.
Supposing we're unable to halt the target,
we'll take measures so that
not a single citizen is killed.
We'll announce an emergency
evacuation drill for Orvud District,
so that if needed, the citizens
will be ready to evacuate at once.
It seems there's no other choice...
The body of our target
is the largest we've seen.
As such, it presents an easy target.
Wall-mounted cannons should
prove highly effective, but...
If that's not enough to bring it down...
The Scout Regiment will throw
everything we have at it.
As part of this drill, dummy Titans
and cannons will be used!
It'll be a large-scale exercise
like nothing you've seen before!
However, we ask you not to panic!
Remain calm and follow our...
Ma'am.
I gotta get my store ready for the day,
so can't you let us go home?
Customers won't be coming today.
Take the day off.
I don't think so, lady.
What's with the drills
when we're so far north?
The military outs the
government, and now this?
What do you mean?
I'm saying this is all just a
demonstration of their power.
To prove that now the fake King is gone,
they're the ones in control.
So, we're being dragged through
this for no reason at all?
Yeah.
At this rate, I think I prefer the
fake King, even if he was incompetent.
H-Hey! Look over there!
Smoke?
Fire!
Well, how's that...?
The ground cannons seem
even less effective.
Of course they are.
The wall cannons barely hit the nape,
even with the better angle.
What's the problem?
It's a mishmash of soldiers...
Cannons they scraped together...
Superficial leadership...
To top it off, this is a northern region.
Unlike troops on the front lines,
they have no battle experience.
However, this is the best we're
going to get, and that's a fact.
Yeah, that much is painfully obvious.
Yet again, your strategy for the Scouts
boils down to another gamble.
Just like everything else you conjure up.
Erwin! I brought the goodies!
All the gunpowder, ropes,
and netting I could find!
We'll have to assemble it ourselves though.
Oh, and this! There's another
on the opposite side.
The trigger's held in place,
so when it's fired,
it'll wind itself back up,
just like ODM gear.
So, is the artillery doing any damage?
Slightly more than a pissing insect.
Then we're really planning on using this?
Levi, Jean, Sasha, Conny...
Take care of that side.
Roger!
How should we do this? Let's see...
Try to imagine we're wrapping up
a nice gift for someone special...
I believe you've heard from Levi, Historia.
Supposing we live through this,
we'll have you become the Queen,
ruling our world in the walls.
Naturally, having you on the
front lines poses a problem.
I doubt it will work.
You think the people so naive that
they'd bow to a ruler in name only?
What is it that you're thinking?
Fire!
Historia...
Just look how strong she's become...
For the longest time,
I thought she was the weak one.
I had it wrong.
The weak one was me.
Somewhere along the line,
I thought myself special.
Which is why, when other
soldiers died for my sake...
...I accepted it like it was natural.
The same goes for my Titan powers.
I hated Titans more than anything...
...but when I became one,
I thought nothing of it.
I wanted to believe that
strength was all mine.
That's exactly how a weakling thinks.
What's the next step?
So what if I'm able to plug up the wall?
Is that enough to save humanity?
I'm not special, I'm nobody.
But... it's all of humanity that
got the short end of the stick...
...being stuck with me as their trump card.
Hey.
The kids in this city remind me...
...of us on that day.
Yeah...
Nobody thinks today is the day
a Titan bigger than the wall attacks.
They might end up seeing the
same sight as we did that day.
But there's one big difference.
Atop the walls, soldiers
stand to face the Titan.
And that would be us.
Yeah, stack it up on the edge.
Eren.
There's no time to stop.
Keep your hands busy.
Eren!
Wh-Whoa!
What are you doing?!
Making a wound? It's too early for that!
No...
Just beating the shit
out of a useless brat.
I hope he's dead and gone for good.
Adjust your aim for a moving target!
Focus all cannons on its nape!
Fire!
Good! That ripped off its flesh!
Finish it off with a volley!
Argh, hot!
Shit, not good...
The wind changed direction!
Captain! I can't see a thing!
Doesn't matter! The target
is straight below! Fire away!
Are we too late?
It's a Titan...
Titan!
Wait! Don't go anywhere!
Shut up!
Retreat! Everyone, retreat!
Shit... It's breaking through...
The city I grew up in...
...is done for.
Stand back, Captain.
We'll take over from here.
Eren, we're up.
Right.
Armin, another thing's different from then.
Eh?
It might not be all they
hoped for, but now...
...humanity has an ace up its sleeve.
Is that... a Titan?!
We're good to go!
Let the attack...
...commence!
Take this!
Yes! It's losing balance!
Eren!
So you're saying...
In order to defeat that Titan...
...we'll stuff gunpowder into its throat...
...and hope it's enough
to blow up its nape?
Correct.
With the heat that it's producing,
I imagine it'll ignite without a detonator.
So as long as it hangs its mouth
wide open for us like an idiot...
An explosion against its nape
won't have the desired effect.
Which is why the explosion
must go off from the inside.
But the target may be protecting itself
by dragging its face along the ground.
For all we know, it may not
even have a mouth to open.
That's the gamble this time.
Jackpot!
All troops! Finish it off with ODM gear!
It may be gigantic,
but its vitals are still one meter high
and ten centimeters across.
Unless we destroy the main body, it will
regenerate and form another shield of heat.
We've only got one shot.
Hot!
Shit! Which is it?!
Historia?!
I understand your reasons, but...
I can't approve you entering combat.
Commander, please!
I've finally grasped the duty
I was meant to fulfill!
That's why I'm here right now!
Well, in any case...
With my body as it is...
I can't exactly stop you, can I?
I'm sorry for being so selfish.
But this is the first time
I've gone against my parents...
This is my first fight... with my father.
Father!
Listen to me, Father!
We can kill the Titans, once and for all!
Why?! Why don't you understand?!
You know I'll be fine, Brother.
Pray for me...
Alma, you're the only one
who understands me...
Leave it to me, Father.
I won't lose to the
ghosts of our ancestors!
Oh, God...
Was our city just saved?
Hey... You okay?
Are you injured?
Were you the one who
dealt the finishing blow?
Was that all... my imagination?
Am I... really...
...acting on my own accord?
I... don't know.
But...
The one always going with the flow is...
...without a doubt, me.
I am...
I am Historia Reiss.
The true ruler of the walls.
I'm afraid... I cannot die right now.
Please, forgive me.
Gimme a damn break...
You hear me, don'tcha?
Gotta name?
That's why I'm able to
do any job asked of me.
Are you any different?
Doesn't matter to me.
It's all pointless anyways.
Captain Ackermann!
Idiots! Get away!
Kenny.
Oh, gee...
It's you?
Your comrades we fought...
They all ended up getting crushed.
Are you the only survivor?
Seems that way.
Report back. I'm fine here alone.
Understood.
With those burns and that blood loss...
...there's no helping you now.
Yeah?
I wonder...
Levi stumbles across Kenny
on the brink of death.
In his hazy and fading mind...
...he remembers the man
he once called a friend.
Next episode: "Friends."
"Friends"